https://www.mplsrad.com/privacy-policy/

Resources
Minneapolis Radiology Associates LLC (MRA) is committed to protecting the privacy of any health information we receive. MRA has established policies on how our employees manage this information. This MRA Privacy Policy describes how your health information may be used and disclosed by our office and also how you may access and control your health information.
MRA Health Information Duties:
When we talk about “Health information,” we include information about your past or present health status, condition, diagnosis, treatment, prognosis, or payment for health care.
MRA has a legal duty to protect the privacy of your health information and to give you this Policy
MRA has a legal duty to abide by our current Privacy Policy
MRA may change the terms of this Policy and make the new terms effective for all health information in our control, including health information we created or received before we made the changes.
MRA will make a revised Policy available in hard copy. MRA will also display the current Policy in our facilities and on our Web site.
Request the revised Policy in-person or by mail.
MRA’s Patient Notice of Privacy Practices
MRA may use your health Information may be used for the following purposes:
Treatment: MRA will use your information to provide, coordinate and manage care and treatment. For example we will release films and reports to other health providers involved in your care.
Payment: MRA will use information to receive payment for services we provide. We will disclose information to submit bills or claims to insurance companies and/or Medicare or State funded plans. When a patient neglects to make timely payments on balance due, MRA may use a collection agency.
Health Care Operations: MRA will use information for certain activities related to our business functions. We may use or disclose information for quality assurance activities.
Appointment Reminders and Treatment Alternatives: MRA may contact you to remind you of an appointment or to reschedule your appointment. Your health information may be used to inform you about health care services that may be of interest to you.
Family Members or Individuals Involved in Your Care: MRA may agree to have verbal information about your treatment or diagnosis shared with a family member or designee. If you are unable to make health care decisions, MRA may disclose relevant health information to family members or other responsible individuals involved in your care. For example, you may give verbal consent for a radiologist to share with your designee information about your procedure.
Other Uses or Disclosures: MRA may disclose or use information in the following situations:
for public health activities, for instance as those activities relate to victims of abuse/neglect/domestic violence
for health oversight activities
for judicial and administrative proceedings to the extent permitted by law
for law enforcement purposes, as permitted or required by law
to coroners/medical examiners/funeral directors, as permitted by law
for organ donation purposes
for research purposes under certain circumstances
to avert a serious threat to health or safety
for certain specialized government functions, such as military discharge, national security and intelligence
for workers’ compensation purposes
Your Individual Privacy Right as a Patient includes the following:
Inspection and Copy: You may make a request in writing to review or order a copy of your health record, with the exception of information protected by law. However, we ask that you obtain your report from your ordering physician before we will make a copy available to you. MRA limits your health records to films, reports and billing information of imaging procedures you received. MRA has the right to ask you for this request in writing and we will respond within a reasonable time frame. There may also be a reasonable charge for copies.
Confidentiality: You have the right to make a request in writing that MRA provide you with your health information. If you request that we mail information to another address, we will agree to your request to the extent we are able to assure accuracy in doing so.
Restrict Use and Disclosure: You have the right to make a request in writing that MRA not use health information in certain ways or for certain purposes. You may also request that we not provide health information to certain individuals. However, MRA has the right to refuse your request, particularly as the law requires.
Change Information or Amend Health Records: You have the right to request in writing that we correct information in your health record if we were the originator of such information. If your request is denied, you may write a statement of disagreement with the denial that we will keep with your health information.
Accounting of Disclosures: You have the right to make a request in writing for an accounting of disclosures of health information that was made without your signature.
Privacy Violations: If you feel your health information privacy rights have been violated, you may file a complaint with MRA’s contact person listed below or with the Secretary of Health and Humans Services. Filing a complaint will not affect the quality of the services you receive at MRA’s imaging facilities and you will not be retaliated against for filing a complaint.
We are glad to have you as a patient, and we will work hard to protect your health information.
Privacy Officer
Jennifer Bahe
PRIVACY OFFICER
2800 Campus Drive, Suite 30
Plymouth, MN 55441
(763) 398-2216
(763) 398-2233 fax
U.S. Department of Health & Human Services
Office for Civil Rights, Region V
233 N Michigan Avenue, Suite 240
Chicago, IL 60601
Phone: 312-886-2359
Fax: 312-886-1807
Organizations Covered by this Notice:
This Policy applies to the privacy practices of MRA clinic locations and subsidiaries listed below. We may share health information within the organization for treatment, payment or health care operations.
Minneapolis Radiology – Maple Grove
9855 Hospital Drive, Suite 150
Maple Grove, MN 55369
(763) 398-6363
(763) 398-6364 fax
Minneapolis Radiology – Plymouth
2800 Campus Drive, Suite 20
Plymouth, MN 55441
(763) 398-2232 fax
This Policy takes effect June 20, 2011 and remains in effect until we replace it.
Analytics
MRA is committed to your privacy. We do not collect, sell or otherwise distribute your information to sources outside our company except when necessary to fulfill the agreed service terms.
Types of Information We Collect and Use:
The Web Site collects and saves only the default information customarily saved by web server software. Such information may include the date and time of your visit, the originating IP address, and the pages and images requested.
Like most Web sites, MRA Web sites also collect and log information automatically and through the use of electronic web beaconing tools that may be transparent to you, such as your IP address, the name and location of your Internet Service Provider, the type and version of your browser, the length of time that you stay on MRA Web sites, search queries, your click-stream data, the location that referred you to MRA Web sites and the average number of pages viewed.
If you visit another Web site prior to browsing MRA Web sites, that Web site might place information within a URL, such as search queries, which may be logged by us. Your IP address is the identifier assigned to your particular computer when you access the Internet. Depending on how you connect to the Internet, your IP address may always be the same, or it may change each time you access the Internet. Note that logging your IP address does not provide us with personally identifiable information such as your name, e-mail address or home or work address.
MRA does sell, rent or trade any personally identifiable information you provide when using our website. We do not collect any personally identifiable information about you (such as your name or email address) unless you specifically decide to provide such information.
Changes and Updates to This Policy:
We reserve the right to change the information, services, features and policies at any time. We will post changes to this and any other policies on this website in writing.
Contact Information:
If you have any questions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:
Minneapolis Radiology Associates, LLC.
Copyright © 2019  ·  Minneapolis Radiology Associates, LLC.  ·  Privacy  |  Terms  ·  Website by Ali’i Design
Our Locations
Areas of Expertise
Our Providers
About Us
MPLS Portal  |  Language Assistant Services  |  Nondiscrimination and Accessibility Statement  |  Site Map
